# Dinesh Chidipothu

### **Profile**

Computer science student with experience in full-stack development through remote internships, opensource contributions, and personal projects.

Love working on challenging problems in the world of software engineering. Curious to learn new technologies. Code quality and maintainability are my priorities.

# Professional Experience

#### **Contributor**, Zulip - opensource chat □

09/2019 - present

- Worked on various backend issues including, but not limited to, integration of a few authentication backends -- Sign in with Apple, GitLab OAuth.
- Improved existing authentication system through multiple patches.
- Implemented typing indicators and read receipts.
- Applied multiple refactors to improve code quality along with addition of new tests

Check out all my pull requests to zulip in GitHub. ☑

### Google Summer of Code Student Developer, Zulip - opensource chat ☑

06/2021 - 08/2021

- Added read receipts feature, extended typing indicators to work for streams and configurability settings for those.
- Various other high priority projects.

Check out my GSoC 2021 final work report ☑ to know more.

### Google Summer of Code Student Developer, Zulip - opensource chat I

05/2020 - 08/2020

- · Worked on several backend projects
- Ported casperJS tests to puppeteer eliminating non-deterministic failures.

Find an overview of all projects I worked on during this time in my GSoC final work report  $\square$ .

#### **Software Engineering (Testing Automation) Intern,** ATG.world □

06/2019 - 09/2019

- Wrote Selenium automation tests for their web app.
- Programmed various non-testing related selenium automation scripts to reduce manual work.
- Helped deploy running a cron job on an AWS server.

# Skills

#### Languages

Frameworks/Tools

Python, JavaScript, C/C++, Java

Django, ReactJS, Flask, Git, vim, pdb

## Projects

## Effective Feedback Management System, Django web app 🖸

A web app for to track student feedback and complaints in a university with features such as like, comment, etc.

#### PapaMeet, Browser extension □

A browser extension to automate the process of joining and quitting google meet. It also notifies if a keyword is being said in the meet.

### Instagram Commentor, Django web app 🛮

A web app for amateur content creators running Instagram pages to comment on new posts posted by reputed pages automatically as a trick to increase reach. Uses Celery and Redis for queuing.

### **Education**